[Music]
in 2022 the consumer Watchdog nonprofit
group truth in advertising filed a
formal complaint with the Better
Business Bureau against juice plus a
multi-level marketing company that sells
supplements the nonprofit claimed that
juice plus had been making deceptive and
unsubstantiated claims for years for
instance saying its products can protect
against everything from covid to cancer
this wasn't the first time truth and
advertising complained year after year
going back to 2016 and continuing into
2023 how have Regulators responded in
2020 the Federal Trade Commission issued
a warning letter to Juice Plus for
unlawfully advertising that his product
can treat or prevent covid and also for
misrepresenting that those who join
their multi-level marketing scheme would
likely earn substantial income you can
totally advertise your product can
prevent or treat any disease including
covid if you can provide evidence to
substantiate your claim but there was no
such study for juw plus and the company
also had to immediately cease making
false and misleading earnings claims in
2023 the Better Business Bureau
published its report saying it is
incumbent on the company to provide
reliable and competent scientific
evidence to support its claims to which
Juice Plus replied that its claims are
based on not one not two but 40
peer-reviewed scientific Publications
and invited the Better Business Bureau
to check out its website and presumably
to its dismay the Better Business Bureau
actually
did of course even if a company has
valid studies that doesn't mean those
studies actually support the claims
being made for example it says its
product helps with depression and mood
but there weren't any studies on
depression or mood same with claims
about brain fog or long-term memory
improvement they wen't studied on one of
its TV infom Marshals a doctor
referenced one of its studies suggesting
Juice Plus might help with weight loss
or colon cancer two things the study
didn't even measure and the Better
Business Bureau raised concerns about
the reliability of the studies in the
first place for example take the family
health study which claimed that more
than half of kids were missing less
School taking fewer drugs and having
fewer doctor visits but that wasn't a
study as much as it was just a survey of
people who could profit from selling it
I mean no control group no randomization
no nothing in terms of actual studies
they funded their modus operandi appears
to be to measure so many different
outcomes that a few will pop up
statistically significant just by chance
like in that supposed weight loss colon
cancer study the researchers didn't
track Weight Loss or cancer but they did
measure 70 other things and didn't get a
single significant result on any
clinical iCal outcome after controlling
for multiple testing same thing here
with gum disease when you test 54
outcomes two products at three different
times in N9 different ways one would
expect a few random positive outcomes
just by chance alone or the Juice Plus
funded researchers just lie about it
here they claim in the abstract that
juice plus improved metabolic profiles
by reducing systemic inflammation in
cholesterol did they think no one would
actually look at the data no significant
change in any of the cholesterol levels
compared to Placebo or any of the
measures of inflammation nor blood sugar
control and the only reason
triglycerides looked better it wasn't
that they got better in the Juice Plus
group but they just got worse in the
placebo group and there wasn't any
significant benefit over Placebo in
weight body composition blood pressure
pulse or physical or mental quality of
life I mean you'd think at least
something would pop up as a fluke at
least it appears to only be a waste of
money uh concerns have been raised about
dietary supplements like Herbal Life and
Juice Plus that could lead to serious
health consequences but although that is
definitely true of verbal life I can
only find a single case report of liver
toxis the attributed to Juice Plus and
the liver injury was reversible after
stopping it here are some measures of
liver damage spiking after starting
Juice Plus and thankfully coming down
after stopping
it for